[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard hey
guys I hope you're doing well Shane Lee
and I are just in the car now we're
heading out of town for a camping trip I
wanted to get this episode out so I'm
recording this quick thing on my phone
right now
this is gonna be butted up against a
like four four and a half minute podcast
clip from the Dark Horse podcast with
Bret Weinstein and Heather hi Heather is
reading a quote from a book by Sebastian
Junger Junger called tribe and it's just
so profound I found myself listening to
literally had to rewound it I listened
to it again
well that's a great excerpt from this
book and then I had to record again so
hopefully I don't get any strikes
against the old account here anything
but I took a four minute clip from the
Dark Horse podcast of her reading a book
of Sebastian Junger and I'm gonna play
it right now and that'll be the internal
podcast we'll get right go into my
conversation with Devin Sims so I hope
you enjoy it I hope you're taking care
of yourself
hope you're drinking tons of water I
hope you guys have a wonderful week take
care
today's veterans often come home to find
that although they're willing to die for
their country they're not sure how to
live for it it's hard to know how to
live for a country that regularly tears
itself apart along every possible ethnic
and demographic boundary the income gap
between rich and poor continues to widen
many people people live in racially
segregated communities the elderly are
mostly sequestered from public life and
rampage shootings happen so regularly
that they only remain in the news cycle
for a day or two to make matters worse
politicians occasionally accuse rivals
of deliberately trying to harm their own
country a charge so destructive to group
unity that most past societies would
probably have just punished
as a form of treason it's complete
madness and the veterans know this in
combat soldiers all but ignore
differences of race religion and
politics within their platoon it's no
wonder many of them get so depressed
when they come home I know what coming
back to America from a war zone is like
because I've done it so many times
younger Trites first there was a kind of
shock at the level of comfort and
affluence that we enjoy but that is
followed by the dismal realization that
we live in a society that is basically
at war with itself people speak with
incredible contempt about depending on
their views the rich the poor the
educated the foreign-born the President
or the entire US government it's a level
of contempt that is usually reserved for
enemies in wartime except that now it is
applied to our fellow citizens unlike
criticism contempt is particularly toxic
because it assumes a moral superiority
in the speaker contempt is often
directed at people who have been
excluded from a group or declared
unworthy of its benefits contempt is
often used by governments to provide
rhetorical cover for torture or abuse
contempt is one of four behaviors that
statistically can predict divorce and
married couples people who speak with
contempt for one another will probably
not remain United for long the most
alarming rhetoric comes out of the
dispute between liberals and
conservatives and it's a dangerous waste
of time because they're both right the
perennial conservative concern about
high taxes supporting a nonworking
underclass is entirely legitimate roots
in our evolutionary past and shouldn't
be dismissed out of hand early hominids
lived a precarious existence where
freeloaders were a direct threat to
survival and so they developed an
exceedingly acute sense of whether they
were being taken advantage of by members
of their own group but by the same token
one of the hallmarks of early human
society was the emergence of a culture
of compassion that cared for the ill the
elderly the wounded and the unlucky in
today's terms that is a common liberal
concern that also has to be taken into
account those two driving forces have
coexisted for hundreds of thousands of
years in human society and have been
duly codified in this country as a
two-party political system the eternal
argument over so-called entitlement
programs and more broadly over liberal
and conservative thought will never be
resolved because each side represents an
ancient and absolutely essential
component of our evolutionary past so
how do you unify a secure wealthy
country that is sunk into a zero-sum
political game with itself how do you
make veterans feel that they are
cohesive society that was worth fighting
for in the first place I put that
question to Rachel Yehuda of Mount Sinai
Hospital in New York City
Yehuda has seen up close the effect of
such antisocial divisions on traumatized
vets if you want to make a society work
she writes she said to me then you don't
keep underscoring the places where
you're different you underscore your
shared humanity I'm appalled by how much
people focus on differences why are you
focusing on how different you are from
one another and not on the things that
unite us the United States is so
powerful that the only country capable
of destroying her might be the United
States herself which means that the
ultimate terrorist strategy would be to
just leave the country alone that way
America's ugliest partisan tendencies
could emerge unimpeded by the unifying
effects of war the ultimate betrayal of
tribe isn't acting competitively that
should be encouraged but predicating
your power and the excommunication of
others from the group that is exactly
what politicians of both parties try to
do when they spew venomous rhetoric
about their rivals that is exactly what
media figures do when they go beyond
criticism of their fellow citizens and
openly revile them reviling people you
share a combat outpost with is an
incredibly stupid thing to do and public
figures who imagine their nation isn't
potentially one huge combat outpost are
deluding themselves unbelievably
brilliant and so many of that so many
lines in there that could take an hour's
worth of conversation it's interesting
to think like like somehow I heard this
thing I think was Daniel SH Martin
Berger who said it and he was talking
about like Society and like what you
know I think like maybe it was like
loneliness or something but essentially
like we're such a lonely society now
that we love just like staring at
people's faces on our phone it was like
oh is that what we're doing yeah I
think that it's something way more
complicated but it's just so simple
we're just like we feel so alone but we
can we can trick that that trigger in
our brains to not feel as alone we could
just stare at people's face when their
stare at a picture that is a crazy
concept it's it's so interesting it's I
love like trying to look at like trying
to look at it from like a biologist
perspective I like what's like what are
humans doing as a creature like not not
just what are we doing you know
but um as a species ya know Devin hey
hey bro cheers man Cheers
it's great to have you I appreciate you
having me out here I love it
yeah I'm glad that you came I think we
were talking about like a while back
going I was first kind of like redoing
things down here I was like sending you
some stuff and showing you so it's it's
exciting that you're able to finally see
it see it as it unravels and I love
everything that you've done down here
with your writing on the wall and just a
vibe the lights and just like your
little your little area where you can
create and just be yourself and let
things flow I love that yeah it's a it's
huge for me like it's definitely I've
always liked my alone space but like
it's insane seeing how much more clear I
feel as a person as a human like just
like my real but we're just feel more
like myself and I really have a place
where it's just like a recharge for me
it's like it's just like my own gas
station down here I just feel whole and
it charges me up it's funny cuz I I
don't know if it's because we're
Scorpios or what but I can relate and
I'm pretty adaptable but when I find a
lot of comfort in as I spend probably a
crazy amount of time just in my car and
I'll be sitting in there whether I'm
watching videos I'll even take my book
and like go drive out to willow or
something and just spend like hours in
my car just zoned out and just really
tuning into myself and my surroundings
and what's going on and yeah it's
awesome
we live in a beautiful area too like I
that's one of my favorite drives going
out there to Willow Grove and mmm you
got rivers you got the greenery around
us it's funny I I was talk about this
hike you know when I was younger I was a
skateboarder and so like bad I yeah
shred but uh you know like bad weather
was always like if I hate rain blah blah
and I was all I had this thing in my
head that I really never thought through
but I was always like just imagine that
I wanted to be somewhere sunny like I'd
always liked it I think what happened is
it was just like this inevitable like
well who wouldn't want to rather live on
a beach that must be nice like to go
surfing whenever you want or whatever
but like realistically
I love being here like
I don't mind the rain and as I get older
as like I'm able to look at my dude
you're not a skateboarder anymore like
you don't have to walk in the rain like
you don't have to suffer like as as you
this years old like I'm 28
like what do I think about rain now what
do I think about the area that I live in
now and when you can look at it like
through new lenses if not like you're a
skateboarder who's like pissed that he
has to walk in the rain for an hour and
he's gonna muddy shoes at school today
like I don't have that anymore and so I
maybe would like to reframe it and be
like oh it's beautiful here
I love it and now you know the last few
years like just mental health wise have
been getting way more into like getting
myself to go outside
I've always liked going outside and like
just being in the woods and hanging out
by myself and stuff but now it's just
it's more and more I'm more appreciating
of this beautiful area that we have here
it good for you because it took for me I
also grew up skateboarding spend a lot
of time hating the rain having no rights
to go to class can die where we got the
one underground part herb
undercover spark I think we skated
together dude I was so it's funny cuz
before the podcast you were talking
about you know being that the guy you
know on the outside or whatever that was
me when you were skating and so like we
would be behind skate or Safeway or
whatever and the squad would be out
there shredding and like I would just
admire watching you guys and me and Jase
Jase and I would be out there just
skating and all Ian when we could doing
a couple cake flips but really admiring
like you guys being out there and
shredding but so cool
yeah so it took for me it took living in
California for the four years and like
always longing to be in a place where I
didn't have to worry what the weather
was going to be like and it was always
going to be you know good weather shorts
and being down there for four years
don't get me wrong I loved it in its own
way but it really made me realize and
appreciate how lucky we are to have as
much rain as we do over here because I
mean without the rain you don't get the
green trees and the fresh air and
everything that we're blessed with in
this area so we I feel like we detach
ourselves from that like you know
everybody knows that like like we know
anybody knows in their head like a man
like
yeah it rains a lot but that's why we
have the beautiful green trees like
that's how all this stuff grows yeah but
it's like in the moment we do get in by
we I mean like me used to you know I'm
sure a lot of people do but I like
complaining about the rain you know and
say it's kinda like complaining about
like you're you this road that you drive
every day has potholes and you're so
sick of it and then they do construction
is lasting for three weeks and you're so
sick of it you're complaining about the
construction in it yeah like come on man
like just deal with what really is
happening here like you know the rainin
ain't so bad if it gives you you know
this yes so it's kind of the it's like
grooves in your mind though I forget who
said it but it might have been on Joe
Rogan too is some shroom guy I forget
what his name is but they were tamil
Tamara's oh my man Paul Stamets might
have been the guy that it was but they
were saying imagine your mind like a
mountain with snow and you're sledding
down creating these grooves in your mind
you know and you're having the same
thoughts and the same negative feelings
towards whatever it is you know the rain
potholes and you're so used to just that
feeling you get you just get used to
reacting in that way and in that podcast
they ended up saying that hallucinogens
kind of leveled the playing field and
like made everything to where your
thoughts could flow freely you know
throughout and you can create new
patterns and new thoughts it was super
interesting but yeah I like that I feel
like I've heard that say like I can't
remember who it was but I feel like I've
heard that because I am sure she I was
like because I mean it's a good one to
think about you know neuroplasticity
yeah you know where that's how our
brains work like will slide right back
in like especially when we need comfort
will slide right back into those deep
grooves you know those things that we've
always been doing that we never the
question why we're doing them and that's
why they're so difficult you know like
the habit change is one of the most
difficult things that we've that we all
face like we want to start eating better
and Bob we know all these things but
then like you know a week later three
weeks later you've slipped back into
those sled divots right there's like
those snow divots um but it's it's
difficult though because when you slide
back into those divots of just like
thinking the same thing all the time you
add this layer sometimes in your own
like oh well I failed right like oh I
slid right back in we think that that's
me I'm the failure like I can't do that
thing that I want because isolated it's
like no no it's like habit change for
the human mind to like get those like
new neuro plastic pathways build them
build and it's difficult but like keep
going don't don't ever say like oh I
slid back into my into my sled path
again I'm stuck in these divots in the
wallet the snow banks on either side are
too big guess this is Who I am like now
that here keep on keep on trying to
get over there if you only get up out of
that divot for a day and you slide it
right back in well maybe try two days
the next time yes and it gives you hope
you know that that one day that you
spent living eating healthy or whatever
it is that you're aiming to do it gives
you the confidence and like I've
experienced myself and anybody that's
tried anything new you know and stuck it
out like playing guitar is a really good
example it is frustrating when you want
to play guitar and you pick up the
guitar and it feels so foreign in your
hands and like your brain doesn't really
know how to work or anything but if you
keep picking it up every day you know
for even a week two weeks a month a year
it gets more and more comfortable in
your hand and like you reach a tipping
point where it just one day just makes
sense you know things just click and if
it feels good and then you can then go
from like learning something to being
creative in your own way and doing doing
what you want to do with that thing
right yeah do you play guitar have you
guitars one of the things where I have
not stuck it through my dad plays drums
and guitar and like I admire him playing
it I was jamming out to Eric last night
on his nocturnal session and like I
admire the way that he can play guitar
but I've experienced getting better and
more comfortable with the guitar and
it's interesting for me because I'm
left-handed right and everything I have
done when I was a child was with my left
side of my body like the right side of
my body just didn't really work and so I
don't have any left-handed guitars I
don't know anybody that plays no Jimi
Hendrix around me or anything to teach
me but so I play right-handed and I've
gotten like
to where it feels more comfortable in my
hand and then life happens and you know
I just I don't stick to jammin out and
so you start back at square one and you
just got to relearn reteach right I mean
that's that's the thing those you know
we out we feel the need to judge
ourselves off of like where we're at
right now of like I don't know the way
that I've been trying to be about
because I'm learning piano in like the
awesome the way that I keep saying in it
it Oh door Kia first like it felt
although I like fickle and kind of like
too overly positive and optimistic but
like now it feels like it's like a no no
I actually believe this like now that I
think I say it to other people out loud
I'm like no I clearly believe this I'm
just like I'm try not to judge myself of
how good I am now or like what I'm doing
now it's like regardless I enjoy playing
piano right and if I continue just
playing piano when I feel when I enjoy
it and I do these you know like I
continue enjoying where I'm at instead
of being mad that I'm not super good I
imagine like how much I'm really gonna
enjoy this in 15 years in 20 years like
you know maybe you're not super great at
guitar piano at this moment but like
that doesn't mean that you do we got a
whole life ahead of us that like if you
just keep chipping away five minutes a
day ten minutes a day 20 minutes two
times a week I mean long form that's
10,000 hours the $10,000 an hour yeah
it's eventually gonna in in we also I
think when it comes to instruments I
feel like I never want to like
disrespect the culture of musicians you
know but because I get that like it
takes hard work and you've got to like
respect like you know if I go up on
stage and look I'm gonna do a jean cover
like you better show out like show some
respect right but there's also parts of
me like just as a creator and as someone
who encourages other creators I'm just
like play play anything put your
fingers on that thing and just play and
suck make anything in in shut in and you
know say oh I that doesn't sound good
but this sounds good okay cool and then
learn about that like look it up google
it or just play that same note that
sounds good and learn about it learn
about how it makes your body feel yeah
you know that's how it was with me with
guitar too
like one day I'm glad that you bring
that up too because it's tough to not
judge yourself it's so natural for us to
like instinctively just start judging
ourselves when you try especially when
you try something new but I remember one
day after trying it was like a week when
I was committing to playing the guitar
you know every day and towards the end
of the week it was getting more and more
comfortable and I really just started
zoning out and like I would just try to
like feel the music and like you you
know I don't really know how to explain
it but you know if you're higher up on
the neck of the guitar it's gonna sound
different than where if you're closer to
like the bridge right and so if you move
in between there you can kind of guess
how the sound will differ you know and
so I was just spending time zone and now
and just like whatever felt or sounded
good and just like appreciating whatever
it was that was coming out of it right
you know that's like such a beauty of
learning an instrument like um you know
our school system like the way that all
of us in the Western world learned is
you know or a lot of the world I guess
is great it's like I'm pass or fail all
right you know yes or no or a good or a
bad so I think that we go about our life
in those same ways like it's like you
know judging our self is literally like
I'm good at this or I'm bad at this yeah
like we don't have to do that we don't
have to live our life through those
lenses at all it's just louder bro all
right yeah and it's it's just crazy I
mean you get so you know all have
moments where I'll you know I'll get
super stoned and I'll you know maybe I'm
having a bad day and I'm just sitting in
front of my piano and like maybe I'm
crying and drooling snot rockets onto my
keys but like it feels good and I'm
experiencing this emotion and I'm seeing
where it takes me because you know I'm
gonna die one day
I'm gonna be I'm gonna you know we're
all gonna die one day and I want to be
able to say that like I you know I I
didn't want to feel weird when I'm
buying myself like you thinking that I'm
not allowed to do this like there's a
gatekeeper that's saying like bro you're
not allowed to how did you cut out yeah
I'm cut out yeah so wiggle the oh it's
because the dog is chewing on it blue
did it split all the way through little
I read a little turd all right I'll
get you new pair headphones Hannah I
love you you my boy I love you Oh blue
anyway so believing yourself and
drilling your snot on keyboard just do
it man just turn the lights down low and
just make some music and just like
figure out like just have the human
experience of sound you know like it
doesn't have to be right or wrong and
you don't have to show anybody you don't
have to post anything like you don't
have to do it for anybody else you
there's this scary like there is a
respect right of like you see somebody
shredding with a guitar and your can you
hear okay are you good
I hear great yeah he's actually after a
few hours of I'm wearing glasses if I'm
like DJing with those ones I'm like a
little headache you know but they're
they're super comfy other way in any way
ma'am I just think it's it's important
for people to like let themselves
experiences these things we put a gate
keeper up when we don't need to there's
a respect like you know don't don't
yourself and like think that
you're like the best whatever and try to
compare yourself to different different
singers and musicians and stuff but you
know if you talk to a lot of musicians
they're probably to say like yeah dude
just try it just play just get in your
get in your room and turn the lights
down low and and just screw off and just
see how it sounds my dad that's how he
taught himself how to play drums and
like he would listen to his favorite
tracks and try to recreate it you know
by jamming out in his room or whatever
and mm-hm
yeah it's awesome I it's one of my
favorite things to watch and I'm lucky
growing up that my dad's always been in
a band so he had meaning of 16 and I
think the band
GBH see that he had still plays with his
buddies to this day but I think they
made that when they were like 17 but I'd
be in my room you know cleaning or
hanging out doing my thing and just
they'd be in the basement jamming out
and
like subconsciously listening to those
songs everyday even if I wasn't
listening like I would I would like
start singing along you know like when I
would go watch and play or a show or
whatever and like you can catch it but
being down there and being able to watch
him and his friends jam out and just
totally like Zone in together and just
like now they're at the point where my
dad will just be playing a beat or
whatever and then mike has buddy will
come and they'll jam together so
beautifully you know because they know
how each other play and like such a cool
thing to watch and experience oh it
really is it's it's that's such a cool
dynamic you know it's something that
like if you're if you're not looking too
closely you might miss it but if you you
know listener if you go to a show and
it's your favorite person right you know
it's Billie Eilish it's Dermot Kennedy
it's it's you whoever and they have a
band a lot of times we over it like
we're so obsessed with like that one
sing or that one like main spotlight but
like if you actually look at John
Billings good example like it's very
interactive with his band and it's this
like the coolest thing to me is seeing
the singer the lead singer or even like
the bass player look at the guitar
player or the drummer that with the
people in the band look at each other
and they have such a long conversation
but it's it's instant right it's like
they communicate so much to each other
on stage and you get to see this like
you know if you're in the audience and
you're like looking at the bass player
and you notice he kind of glances over
the drummer and they both kind of start
smiling and they're like and you know
they're kind of building up and you
could feel that the song's about to have
a change and then just they just create
this new thing together through them
just looking at each other and
communicate oh it's so it's like my
favorite things man it's it's humans
fascinate me when it comes to music one
yeah music and itself and what you're
explaining right there is like the way
that you can communicate without words
like that fascinates me too you know
like being able to just look at somebody
and know what they're trying to say to
you pick that up that's well I mean like
like we were talking about earlier I was
using the analogy of as you're driving
down the freeway in your metal box like
you look over and all of a sudden dude
next to you looks right back at you
because he kind of felt he had a feeling
like you know if you you look up at a
semi-truck driver and within a few
seconds he's literally gonna look at you
it's just he senses somehow that you
were looking at the guy so uh you know
music is words are so beautiful and so
important but what are we trying to do
with words here we're trying to describe
feelings yeah that's what we're trying
to do instance sometimes there's like
there's not enough words that describe
the feeling so warm words messing up or
words just don't quite get it right yeah
just you know give it justice yeah it
yelling and that's that's such a beauty
in music is like they can say something
they can communicate something that's
it's very important you're like I don't
know how it's important I'm not really
know how to explain how it's important
in words but like that was important
like that was and I love music yeah I
envy people that can create yourself you
know and being able to try to translate
that feeling or whatever through your
music that's just right I live I like it
because I notice it you know what I mean
when I'm listening to people and their
music I really tried to Zone in and
appreciate what they're doing and
creating and like a lot of the times you
can feel what it is you know the
build-up or whatever it is and as a DJ
I'm sure you admire that because anybody
creating music that's what you try to do
right simultaneously edge of creating
music you want to read the crowd and see
what they're responding to what they're
not really digging you know and right
there's that unspoken communication
between everybody all right it's a it's
you know crap crowds crowds and music
are interesting I've been thinking about
like audiences and like crowds and like
I had a good conversation with my
comedian friend Joe about about kind of
the same thing about how you know the
audience almost has to wrote so there's
so when it comes to DJing like what's
the difference between like Skrillex and
a wedding DJ right like you know DJ is
put next to their name but like they're
so different and it's like I think that
people who don't play music don't really
think about it much but you know you're
not going to hire a metal band to play
acoustic guitar at your wedding
right there's different things so you
have to like put the right music and
music style with the right audience
then there's also like there's this
other area of music that's like hey I
have something to say
like like here's what's what I'm trying
to communicate in what so like so when
I'm DJing and I'm paid for it I'm paid
for the gig like I'm trying to read the
people through it like people are
walking through the door and I'm you
know kind of subconsciously glancing at
them what are they wearing how old are
they what what does it look like they
might listen to like there's this like
kind of getting a feel for the crowd and
like that's a DJ you're trying to like
you're not taking everybody's favorite
song and smashing it together
you're not taking only the popular songs
and forcing them to listen to what you
know is gonna work what I'm trying to do
is I'm trying to like freely just get
the vibe like I'm almost like internally
judging every person in that
room you know it's what a DJ does he
looks it the whole of the he's he's
trying to get the feel the vibe whatever
of the room and try to and try to curate
it and bump it in certain places and
make people feel certain things and get
people to feel certain nostalgia but
also you know present at the same time
but so there's that when it comes to
like DJing and there's this expectations
of like you're feeding the room of
people who aren't here just for you
they're here to have a good time their
self so you're just trying to contribute
to that right right but then there's
also this side of artistry and music and
even DJing of like we're coming here to
hear what you have to say because you
have to say it in a way that nobody else
does like when I first arted saying
Skrillex for example I mean holy
like the dude was doing nothing that
anybody else was doing as far as I had
seen you know and so I wasn't looking to
like go to get my needs met in my
expectations and like I hope I hear my
favorite song tonight it's like this
person is standing on stage like reading
their poetry that they wrote in their
basement alone practically you know so
there's this there's different sides of
of like music and in communication of
music when it comes to like deejays and
electronic music and bands and
everything it's just it's it's it's been
in I think I brought it up it's been a
journey because I've been doing the DJ
thing for so long but I also have like
felt like an artist like
I always want to like I haven't like
produced a ton of my own music like when
I was like DJing like playing all these
things and playing all these clubs and
stuff like I went really playing my own
stuff like I'll play like mashups and
I'll do my edits and stuff but the last
since I've been playing piano and like I
loved songwriting I'm not good at it but
I love it but it's it's this whole
different side of me that I'm like in my
basement trying to like say and figure
out what I have to say and like try to
write something authentically from my
heart but then like then just thinking
of how I would take that and then like
sing it on a stage that just seems like
madness like that's just what a hard
thing to do though like the fact that
you're even seeking out to do something
like that and you're embarking on that
journey yourself it's not easy but the
fact that you're doing it like kudos to
you man that's crazy
right yeah it's it's it's enjoyable I
like you say that's one of the most
challenging parts of DJing and or
creating music or I guess the question
would be what is the most challenging
part for creating music or DJing Humber
you you know lately I have this thing on
my keyboard I wrote don't strangle it
for me it's been trying my best to not
mimic other people because I'm so easily
inspired is my like catchphrase it's
like my favorite like I'm so easily
inspired like if I see like someone's
scene was like a deep voice like I just
I want to try that I want to figure out
I want to see how that sounds with my
throat you know like if I see somebody
singing high-pitched and weird and like
they're writing like these crazy weird
lyrics like I want to see what that's
about but at some point like I'm trying
to make this like cool mashup of like
yeah I've learned this from pull this
from this person imma pull this from
this person and then so so the hardest
part for me has been like not over
trying it but trying to find this like
what's what's me in there like yes it is
a combination of all the things that
I've learned and all the concerts I've
seen and all the artists that I listen
to but I don't want to mimic them but I
also don't want to purposely just try to
be not like that right it's this weird
like is it's a like I said don't
strangle it man yes it's it's I'm trying
to find this complicated like what is
like my
voice like what is my thing that only I
out of these 8 billion people can do and
that's quite the task to put on yourself
right but it's it's beautiful at the
same time because I don't know if I'm
ever gonna complete it I don't know if
I'm ever gonna get there but it's not
really about getting there it's about
like that search of like what do I have
to say and can I actually find a way to
say it and do I have the skills to make
my fingers move in a way that like
coincides with my vocals you know it's
yeah it's it's fun man music is
fantastic you said your dad's still
still plays though it still jams out
it's one of my favourite things to see
him play they did they don't do a bunch
of shows obviously anymore but he has
this new band bear chaser and they
before everything started going on they
had plans to go and tour like down to
some places in California back up
through like Utah Idaho and then coming
back here and that's kind of been on
hold but he's he still plays with like
the same guys that he's always played
with in high school which is really cool
and then you might know his name I went
to Kelso I forget what his last name is
but his name's Alex Alex I forget what
his name his last name is he wore
glasses
I'm gonna feel like there's like a
picture popping up my head I'm not I
know I wish I knew if I I know if I knew
the last name which I'll figure it out
you would know who he is but he's in the
band and yeah they make really cool
music I don't really know how to explain
it but his original band GBH see they're
more like a grungy grungy type of music
you know which was interesting for me to
listen to at a young age because it
seemed everybody that I was going to
school with and my friends and they were
all listening to rap you know or
whatever was new and hip and Here I am
you know growing up we were talking
about before but I'm like this insecure
kid and like my dad was playing this
grungy music you know and driving this
excuse-me band van and I'm like yeah you
can drop me off at the diagnosed
just cool down we're so silly when we're
talking about that stuff it's crazy but
it's awesome now because like what I ran
away from as a kid is like I'm really
prideful now as an adult and so yeah my
dad plays grungy music yeah yeah isn't
that cool how like you know it's just
like I was talking about like I used to
like hate on rain and now that I'm older
and I could see it as like oh it's
actually cool man like it's a train is
how you get this thing so it's like now
like if you got dropped off at school
you like to drop me off right up front
it was cool like see you like that
yeah hell yeah it's really cool like ya
haven't meaning 16 a lot of people were
like man Wow how was that you know and
like it was my dad was a single dad
growing up I spent most of my time with
my dad and like because of that we have
like this Brotherhood bond you know
we're so close an age where now we have
a really good relationship because of it
and yeah he kudos to my dad here because
being 16 and having a kid and like
having to go through all that I couldn't
even imagine or put myself in that
situation but you're forced to grow up
quick and like you've got to assume this
responsibility of another life you know
and he he found a good way and balance
of like still live in his life and
hanging out with his friends and doing
whatever he was gonna do you know and
Here I am running around in the
background and the mix you know but it's
it probably wasn't the best situation
for me to be around as a kid but I don't
I think that it was the best situation
that I could be around as a kid because
I grew up because of it you know I'm
very independent doing my laundry and
stuff when I was a kid you know having
to get my own food things like that they
really make you grow up and we were
talking about like survival instincts
and stuff you know as kids and that kind
of forced that upon me and helped me
grow up and assume that responsibility
so right yeah I mean that's a you know
that's it I originally that's a while
back - I had originally texted you I
think I sent you long text basically
like I just like your outlook on the
world man like I I think that you have a
positive like good healthy and you know
influential to people who want to listen
to it just view on
appreciate that yeah and I and it's cool
that you you know it's not like you had
like sunshine and in roses it's not like
it was like yeah I think that we it's
probably I don't know if it's just
because movies or we don't really think
that much integrally about it but we
always just think like oh they must have
this person must have had this whatever
upbringing and whatever but you know you
start really talking to people and
getting to know them and it's like every
person has like kind of an intricate
upbringing and it was way different than
you thought and it was a they had they
had their hardships but they you can see
like oh that's how you are really good
at this now though yeah how you handled
it and stuff yeah it's really
interesting I could my family is kind of
amazed and I am very lucky and grateful
to have that look that I do have in life
but I had it was the opposite of
sunshine and rainbows growing up you
know and I had everything working
against me my parents were into drugs
when I was before I was born and things
like that and so there's people I went
to school with or whatever and they've
gone through certain things and used
that as an excuse to act out in a
certain way in life you know and I think
what I really learned from it's funny
because I've kind of noticed this too
but it seems like well personally for me
growing up and being around all the
stuff that I was around it kind of
taught me what not to do or what I
didn't want to be like you know not
don't get me wrong my dad's a great guy
but like as far as partaking in the
drugs and everything and stuff like that
that stuff that I could avoid in my life
you know and so I always strive to want
to have a better life or have food on
the table not have to worry about things
like that you know what I mean so I
think that was a big motivation for me a
lot growing up but you see kids that you
they get everything handed to them or
just had this perfect life you know and
then where does that get them in
adulthood you know when they've never
had to work for anything and they've
just had things handed to them you don't
get that real life Drive I guess I don't
know what you'd call it but yeah well I
mean yeah experience like we again we
decoupled ourselves yeah just but is we
decouple ourselves from
you know we're always as humans were I
was desperately trying to define
ourselves right now
you know but it's like you aren't just
who you are now you're just a whole your
whole your the dance man you're not you
you're the in-between here it's like
like we were again right before the
podcast we were talking about like a
little my upbringing like I wouldn't be
in this position like if I had never
been depressed I wouldn't be doing a
mental health podcast to like talk about
people's depression as you know
like I if I didn't have the rough life
that I had I wouldn't have been that
tough I wouldn't have been if I wasn't
forced to like take care of myself at a
young age in in certain ways I I
wouldn't be nearly as resilient or tough
as I am now and like hey I'm sidestep
I've sucked I've done shitty stuff like
I've I'm no perfect human being by any
means but like a lot of the strength and
the you know as I get older especially
the last couple years like a lot of this
is as I kind of look back at my past and
reframe my views of how it was like okay
so like that's how I perceived it here's
how it was okay and I don't it doesn't
help me to go forward in life with that
same perception so like what can I form
from that exact same situation looking
back at my memories like here's here's
what happened how can I form you know my
my next steps around that being well
that's just how I learned this right
that's how life handed me the path of
life handed me those things at that age
so I can learn the things that I know
now yeah you know it's so hard to you
know it's not that simple of course but
like it's so hard to decouple ourselves
from our like past sometimes in those
ways like but I think it's important we
see a lot we see a lot of like the words
childhood trauma on social media and in
the last couple years and I think it's
amazing but I wish there was like a
different word because yeah yeah cuz I'm
as intense well I mean well it could be
the reality though it could be the
oddity but but I think that we you know
I would hate for it to turn into like
everyone who's young who's like trying
to deal with her childhood trauma all of
a sudden is like in fisticuffs against
their parents and their parents just
feel shame like it's not about making
sort of people who raised us like we as
a human species have just gained more
consciousness like more more
intelligence and we're like oh okay like
you know I'm not I'm not a terrible
person but like I did learn how to do
these things because this thing happened
to me so now like I'm realizing I'm
smart enough now in this day and age to
realize like I don't necessarily want to
go forward and do that so yeah I'm able
to like reassess my old story and it
frames like Who I am and how I'm
reacting today it's not like I spit in
the face of parents or anything no no no
but um yeah the journey I it's funny cuz
it doesn't mean ever really make sense
in the midst of it you know something
happens to you and you're thinking why
me or what did I do to deserve this and
it's not that at all but whether it
makes sense to you right now or years
down the road I feel like if you seek
the answer it's definitely gonna show
itself to you and it will all make sense
to you and like for me that gives me the
confidence to keep going and get through
those tough times you know seeing I'm
still here like there's a lot of things
that I've been through good and bad and
like like you said I learned mostly
through the hard times I learned a lot
you know so without those hard times you
wouldn't have those realizations or you
wouldn't dive deep into trying to
understand your own depression like
you're saying and understand yourself
like you do now right which is awesome
yeah and it's it's beautiful man I I
think again it's such a weird time I
wonder how many times want to say it's
weird time but it's you know I feel like
you see more and more the last like a
year or two more people you know mid 20s
late 20s whatever like just kind of
taking a look at at their actions in
their life yeah rephrasing things and
reshaping them I don't know if it's like
we're more emotional I mean we're
definitely like waking up as a society
and people are looking at those things
you know we can we see that all around
us more now than we ever have and it's
awesome but it's almost like we're
getting more in tune with ourselves and
more emotional and trying to like
understand ourselves and people are
asking those questions and
seeking those answers and like because
of that we're gonna you're gonna find
something you know or you're gonna
stumble across something else that might
lead you down another rabbit hole makes
sense you can connect this with that you
know and yeah yeah you don't know what
you don't know man that's right I'm
gonna start unraveling it yeah so you're
positive dude what's up dude what's it
know your father do you're positive we
do this all day
what's your if someone who's just like
bummed all the time if they came out to
you it's an elevator it's just the two
of you the door closes they're like hey
man listen I know this is weird you
don't know me but I just know who you
are you're always nice and you're
positive like what it what do you think
differently than me yeah that's a tough
question to answer but but go ahead and
try that's a great question I think
really what I would do i we were talking
about this before the podcast I I feel
like I can feel like empathetically or
whatever I feel like I can feel what
other people are feeling you know so
maybe this guy gets in the elevator and
I already know something's wrong with
him coming in there and like I would I
mean for anybody if you're going through
a tough time or like you're feeling
bummed out I think it's really important
for me personally you know spending some
time by yourself and asking those
questions and really just trying to find
out where things aren't really lying
enough for you you know maybe you're not
doing something in your life that you
should be doing that's making you feel
some type of way and maybe bringing you
down you know but then again for other
people it's just you the last thing you
want is to be alone you know so I can't
really relate with that because for me I
have a ton of power like being alone and
no matter how sad I am or anything like
I want to feel those feelings internally
and like I think it's important to if
you're feeling some type of way to get
that out whether you get it out with
yourself
write it down piece of paper you tell
somebody you don't I don't want to hold
it on to those feelings you know so if
you need to talk to somebody or whatever
and that works
for you but for me personally I like to
have that conversation with myself first
and really just spend the day by myself
like I was telling you earlier we'll
drive I'll Drive out to willow and just
be by the water be outside and just it
like resets you there's so much going on
I feel like being in the wilderness just
kind of like it's calming you know what
I mean yeah man I'm I'm super in the
same boat I do like nature really resets
me and I I think that I mean again just
kind of coupling it with we're always
trying to define ourselves right now but
you know you're saying like in this
moment in the elevator when someone's
like why are you happy all the time or
why are you happy right now like what do
you got to smile about it's like well
you it's because you didn't you know let
those things fester like you took some
alone time and like let's think about
this and like what do I want and
whatever you know I I think we have some
momentum in her life I totally just
realized like the question that I
thought you're asking me is like
someone's bummed out you know like what
would you do for that guy but I realized
looking like the question was like how
are you so happy and positive well I
mean it's all kind of full circle like
it's it does but I mean we're still
answering the question yeah the answer
continues but I mean as far as being
like positive and happy it's I've
trained myself to just see the good in
things you know and we were also talking
earlier I'm very lucky to be surrounded
by so much love as a kid with my
grandparents especially and you know
that I felt like they were always so
worried about what was going on in my
life and they were so worried that I was
gonna take things a different way than I
did that they there was so much love
surrounding me always you know like
they're always there for me if I need
them or just even people just want to
feel loved so when you feel that there
is people loving you and that was
calming in itself you know but I mean
it's for me a lot of it it's don't be
wrong I get sad I have bad days but like
it's black and white you can be happy or
you can be sad I feel and so I I like to
appreciate the sadness I like to feel
sad but I don't like to dwell on it and
hold on to it you know what I mean so
I'll feel the emotion and I think
because I am Not Afraid to feel that
emotion it helps me let go and move on
and be happier going forward you know
what I mean right yeah there is this I
mean it's it's so hard to like really
conceptualize but there is this a lot of
times when we're feeling the pain or
we're feeling the anxiety we're feeling
like that whatever it's actually we're
keeping it alive by trying to like not
feel it like I'm not actually away
yeah like by trying to like avoid a you
know that's why we're you know we're so
addicted to our phones and we're so
addicted to like you know like like when
you can't sit in a room because like the
crap comes up and you're like I know
let's let's do something else you know
like a lot of your life could be that
momentum you know I think that I think
that like we were talking about we keep
referencing her in conversation before
conversation but like you on the way
here there was like you know on the
freeway there was some duty like wasn't
really letting you over it was like a
traffic you know white road rage
situation of not that you got road rage
but just a traffic situation right where
anybody would you know reasonably be
like come on dude or you're pissed or
you're whatever whatever your level of
behind the wheel anger is like you're
there right yeah well you take the exit
and you know that card keeps driving
down the freeway or whatever like at
what point are you going to choose to
continue feeding that thought or at what
point are you gonna say okay yeah I was
kind of ticked off but anyway that's
that I'm no longer on the freeway I'm
just pulled into my driveway
oh man I'm home that's but you know like
we'll hold on to these things on
accident sometimes and just continue
bringing them back up because we're like
the house so wrong with that guy did
that was so like he cut me off
you know it's so annoying like who
didn't nobody ever teach him
drivin you're you're spending time in
your life trying to figure out this
person of why they got to where they're
at and why they're not thinking the same
way you are in this situation and
well-thought becomes a mood becomes a
personality as Joe Dispenza says have
said they don't hear a couple times but
it's true you know it's it's that
holding on like you actually after a
while of you know four or five minutes a
lot of times of being angry about you
know kind of maybe sometimes fickle
things we have to keep inserting it stay
angry you have to keep bringing
back up right oh you do you got to feed
it the beasts so just notice when you're
feeding the beast yeah you know and you
never know I mean another thing that
helps me out you know you're driving by
and that guy cuts you off or whatever
you never really know what somebody else
is really going through you know that
guy might be rushing to the hospital to
go see his mom one last time or you
really never know like what other people
are going through in their life and for
I I felt that myself you know like I've
caught myself being snappy at other
people and realizing you know I can't
take that out on them you know that it's
nothing that they did they didn't do
anything to make me feel this way you
know what I mean so I'll catch myself
but you never know man there's life's
crazy and things can happen like that
and things could be going really good
for you one minute the next minute your
whole life could be upside down and so
don't get me wrong I get up I get angry
you know road rage I might have slightly
but driving is a very easy way to get me
triggered but I always try to catch
myself and you know remind myself that
you never know what someone else has
going on or right right I'm dude a
road-rage if you really think about it
like it's not that unreasonable like
we're biological we're the thing that
came after apes and we get angry and
like fight things that are trying to
kill her so you're going 70 miles an
hour in a metal box and like someone
like doesn't do the thing that makes
sure you're safe that they don't really
do it 100% like so of course it's like
hey like you like cutting
people off and like putting doing
traffic stuff is really like it's worthy
of getting mad like hey man this is life
and death like we don't screw around out
here this is some serious stuff this is
we don't just oh you were making not
paid any bump into that tree yeah look
like as you're walking through the woods
it's not like oh maybe trip over it oh I
stepped on that log it's like no no
we're going real fast and this is metal
and we could die so there's like these
reasonable things but yeah
not holding on to it it's so important
do you as I was as we're talking about
it I was thinking about the example from
the book seven Habits of Highly
Effective People have you read that one
the audiobook yeah so there was a I'm
gonna butcher cuz it's been a while
since I've since I've read it but
essentially it was like is this story on
like a perspective I think it's when I
had first like kind of learned about my
perspective ran it when I was younger
essentially like there there's this
subway like these people are on the
subway and there's it's from this guy's
perspective of there's this dude next to
him and he this dude has kids and his
kids are just like kind of being rowdy
like his kids are just they're hanging
all over everything they're being loud
they're like and he's not telling his
kids to like guys come on there's other
people on the subway please sit down and
so the the perspective of the from the
rider was like sitting there and like he
could sense you know like people are
getting annoyed he's not the only one
it's like somebody should really say
something to this guy you know so
eventually he just he's like hey man
like what you know just had a long day
of work or whatever it was like could
you could you have your kids calm down
like they're disrupting the whole train
ride and then the father like kind of
comes to and he and he looks around and
he's like oh no and and he says I'm so
sorry of course I guess they're just a
little upset because if we just came
from the hospital their mom just died
you know what I mean like and that's not
the exact story but that's it's pretty
that's perspective for you and and
that's and he talks about afterwards
like how it just like flipped a switch
for me they know you like a freight
train you're like man I feel like a dick
right yeah in you know our perspective
because I remember after I had read that
book this was like in high school it was
like a defining moment for me it was
like and freshly read that book or like
within a couple weeks or something and
some dude had pulled out in front of me
I was on the way to like my high school
girlfriends house and he pulled out in
front like out of nowhere and I didn't
even have a single second of like anger
or like gripping or anything it was
literally just like a I was present at
the moment and I like let off the gas
and he went in front of me because
instantly I was thinking about that book
and instantly I was like oh like maybe
he has like an emergency he just had to
like peel out like what if he just like
has to get and you know likely not but
like what's what's the what's the
positive benefit of me trying to figure
out why this ass will cut me off
yeah of me trying to like figure out why
he's such an and why I'm better
than him and Baba
I think when we look at our own
perspectives it allows other people to
like you know be more lenient with our
perspectives too it's it's cool we can
learn from stories like that too you
know like when you that anecdotal
evidence really sticks with you you know
when you hear a story like that and that
the way that guy felt when you asked
that question because those kids were
acting in that way you know when he was
getting impatient really it really
sticks for me at least you know right
what I feel like you're a book reader I
love books if I had to say just first
thing comes to mind number one book the
light shall set you free
I feel safe all right all right tell me
about it tell listeners about it Oh
unless this book you'll have to read it
for yourself because I believe that I
mean you're gonna get what you want out
of a book you know what I mean we can
read the same book and take something
differently from it but it will
highlight all different sentences man
yeah the whole book I would actually
highlight this whole book every word is
just gold but yeah so it starts off it's
very interesting so this book the time
that I read it like I'm trying to think
of like how to say this but it it's not
a religious book but this book helped me
realize and look at Jesus in that in a
different way than just a religion and
like I can kind of go into what I mean
by that but pull this thing a little
closer so if the book starts off given
like this this background of kind of
what it's going to be about kind of
going into the terminology with this
book it says things like ascended
masters and it talked about chakras and
universal laws and I don't think I ever
remember hearing any of those words
before I read the book and so I dive
into the book and I'm trying to like
think what I can tell you without just
telling you about the whole book
but well I mean it's fine I mean you
can't really explain a whole book even
if you want you just look into it from
your perspective and they'll go read it
yeah so um man what can I even say about
the book yeah I don't even really know
what I could say I do just recommend
like reading the book and taking from it
what you will but it it it led things
that laid things out for me so nicely
for me to understand you know what
chakras are how to how I can use them to
benefit me in my life spiritually and
then it goes in after speaking about the
chakras universal laws and like I got
like so the way that I went for me I got
really into like conspiracies and stuff
and I would stay up you know when I was
a kid for hours just watching YouTube
videos about conspiracies and I yeah and
I found myself living almost in worry
you know so it was like how does this
benefit me if like now I'm living in
this worry that there's something going
on that I can't do anything about and a
years passed and we're in the same boat
nothing's changed like outside except
for the way that I feel inside you know
and so once I got out of the conspiracy
I started like focusing on success
principles right and they it was another
thing for me to kind of dive in to get
lost in and kind of learn about and I
loved the concept of like well through
success principles they brought up the
law of attraction right and like I loved
the idea that at the time I thought I
could just think of whatever I want like
it just happens in my life I was like
great
that's exactly I'm looking for and like
as I search for what the law of
attraction really meant this book ended
up popping up in my life and there's
this part in the back of the book that
talks about the universal laws and it
talks breaks down like more than just a
law of attraction there's I forget how
many but over 15 different universal
laws and then sub sub universal laws and
that book opened up a bunch of like
understanding for me and like
understanding how I could think in this
different way and almost like crack the
code to life you know and like and it
helped me understand how I can just find
answers within myself and how I can like
make my life exactly the way that I want
it to be you know through thoughts and
so that's why I originally started
reading the book but there's it goes
into a lot more stuff other than that
but yeah it's an amazing book it
literally leaves me speechless oh dude I
mean I'm pumped to read it cuz he
brought it up earlier and you're the
same thing you're like dude it's you got
it good yeah the universal law thing
though was a big one for me things like
you know what comes up the law of
polarity what goes up must come down you
know and so help me realize and
appreciate the rain and the darkness in
life because you know how good is the
sunshine without the rain you know what
I mean if it's all you know so you know
we decouple it I think the you know cuz
I started learning about when I was like
started massively just like watching
YouTube videos and like obviously a lot
of the motivational videos and stuff too
like in the morning so I was just trying
to get my mind right you know before I
do my yoga and meditation just get
positive and get like oh yeah okay I do
want to do these things I want to get
this area of success and blah blah llama
traction came up like and I remember I
remember at first like I thought that I
knew about it like I thought I I went
into it like yeah like it I know that
corny oh my god whatever and then
like you start learning about it and I
say you start you know I started
listening to hours and hours of people's
different perspectives on it and people
like you know not so much like here's
here's what I manifested and it gave me
this like not so much that because that
was always like well you know maybe
that's proof that happened to other
people but it doesn't make sense of like
how it works with the reality you know
like but you start learning about this
stuff and Law of Attraction and there's
like more than just the movie the secret
if you've ever seen that one document
like it starts here's the thing I think
that the way that we perceive reality
like the way that we're always trying to
look at realities we're always trying to
what's the truth what's then well that's
not real that's not the truth but like
what is the truth says who you know we
all have different answers when it comes
to truth we all have different ways that
we learned it you know through the
hundreds and thousands of years like
what what it passed down to and I think
that like so for me when I started
learning like the law of attraction
stuff and things in that similar realm
it was just like oh this is this is a
way that I could structure my thoughts
that leads to like positive and not just
like downward spirals and not just
trying to feed my lower conscious
feelings not trying to like it it
allowed me to dream and like put my
dreams in kind of like a plan and let
myself like coz listen man like what
like what what if nobody ever believed
in themself nobody what if Einstein
never believed in himself
what if any actor you've ever seen or
known or any song you've ever heard what
if Jimi Hendrix never believed in
himself that's the thing we have this
like wait like am I am I supposed to
like believe that I actually want those
things like should I act like it's
someone gonna make fun of me if they if
they saw inside my mind and they see
that I'm kind of like wishing that I was
a movie director one day like like you
know we get caught up and like feeling
nervous to even allow ourselves to
believe these things and for me when I
started you know the law of attraction
stuff I started I'm such an open person
like I'm like let's experience it like
it's like maybe like after a couple
months was I've had sometimes like think
about it then I'll decide like I don't
know if I believe that or not but I like
remaining in disbelief in experiencing
things and afterwards like right
afterwards if I feel amazing and it
hasn't like you know harm my life like
it's like oh honey that feels good to
believe those thoughts like why not sit
in that why don't explore that a little
bit more I love ya dude I think I'm
really excited to read that book I want
to learn more about that the other laws
like does it show it's like does it say
anything about like raw and the law of
one and stuff like that and yeah there's
a law of oneness in there it there's a
lot of things that I never really put
into thinking about but there's the law
of oneness and that's another thing the
book talks about
like how how we're all connected you
know and we were talking earlier about
your chakras and the forget how you said
it but your chakras from your like
throat chakra mmm
past your crown chakra and everything
that's like who you were right and that
documentary I was watching before we
came over here the autobiography of a
yogi' he talked about your excuse me
your spine and your chakra energy
centers going up through your body and
then out past your body are like what
connects you to the divine or like
everything the oneness you know and it's
a crazy concept and the more that like
you look into it I feel like the more it
makes sense to you for me and like yeah
I don't know that's a crazy it's a crazy
feeling because there's so many times
that like I've had this one thought and
like why I know you've probably spirit
it to like you're thinking this thing
and then whoever you're with says
something about that thing you know and
it's like everything is connected and
it's it's a trip to thinking about but
it's so like comforting also to think
about you know like role in this
together and just on different journeys
and like different experiences but it's
all like contributing to the same
picture right yeah you know those do
you've read those boots bump those
Goosebumps books like choose your own
thriller like to like your true 2-0 and
like it's like go to this page like if
you would like to do this in this
scenario flip to page 49 or if you would
like to so it was essentially like like
I scared you every the Goosebumps books
yeah are sure so they had some of them
they had I remember I just thought it
was so cool thing I was like you can do
that with a book you can make you can
make me skip those pages and still give
me a story well that's crazy like sister
so essentially you get to you know the
end of chapter one it sets you up like
you meet this person and you follow them
into the woods and then you're at a fork
in the road and they ask if you want to
go to the left side or if you want to go
to the right side what do you do if you
go to the right side turn to page 49 if
you go to the left side turn to page 38
and so you would follow
like choose your own me right I never
know that oh they were super cool yeah I
think they have something similar like
that on Netflix now actually interesting
in some sort of way but I I you know I
think like what if you like a look at
life like that like instead of trying to
think that you like okay I know this to
be a hundred percent true and I know
this is what you do and I have this
knowledge and this is how I stay safe
and not die so I'm just gonna do that
like what if you just like as different
experiences come up in life you say like
hmm so with that like we should I maybe
I should go check out yeah yeah I love
that you say you like to live in
disbelief and like you keep that open
mind throughout things that you do
that's awesome yeah you know I tried to
it's a I you know I'm being a chameleon
like being a chameleon personality type
like being up like match other people I
enjoy it it's a natural thing for me
it's like how it but it's it's how I
learn like a survival technique as we
were talking earlier it was sometimes
there is a little bit of trouble like
trying to find the constant like trying
to find like man what do I believe in
like what what is like my like what
solidifies me in my head like beliefs
you know and like now like over the last
few years I've like established my like
values I've established like what like
what what I want to stick to and like
what divets I'm good with staying in but
I feel like you know now I like
embracing the fact that like I'm not
like a super solid like a okay cutter
yeah like I enjoy being you know ditto
from poker yeah I enjoy like I enjoy
like when someone comes into the room
and they're like exuberant ly happy in
like I can like just try to find the
level that they're on and explore like
why they're happy and what what they're
about and instead of just like thinking
about myself and this whole time it's
you know life opens up and you learn
more about people and you know you get
to choose your own adventure as you go
along that's right it makes it
interesting it's cool it's fun being
like how to win friends and influence
people have you ever read that book no I
have
I've read the the synopsis like yeah the
bleakest so what's interesting what that
book what I took from that book is you
know being interested in other people
and so you know when you come in to
meeting with somebody instead of being
so self-absorbed with yourself you know
really taking an interest into what
makes them who they are you know and
dude that's that's actually this is a
cool place because that is kind of
there's not avoidance but that's kind of
an antidote to anxiety like or
self-consciousness
so for listeners who reef so you're
saying that looking in to find out how
other people is a sign of that
interesting so a lot of times we walk
into a room so say you're anxious say
you're you're feeling like one of those
nights where it's just like
self-absorbed we're kind of thinking
about yourself and you're like our
people don't like my outfit or all right
you know we all get it like I have a zit
on my face or I'm a little too drunk
walking into this new bar is everybody
looking at me and wondering if I'm the
most wrong person here it's like for one
nobody's thinking about you
probably but for two you know in that
same spot like sometimes our minds could
get caught in these loops of like
insecurity sometimes and just constantly
like are they thinking this about me are
they thinking this about me you're
trying to like figure out what everybody
else is thinking about you but like as
an antidote to chaos in that area you
could almost like I'm not even gonna
think about myself at all I'm not even
gonna think do I like these people do
they like me I'm just gonna try to like
them I'm just going to learn about them
I'm just gonna ask them questions about
them and you'll notice like you know 15
minutes later you're in this like
interesting conversation and this dude
is like you never expected to but he's
been a librarian for 30 years right
having a good conversation about books
or something you know yeah and then
you'll realize like oh I'm not even
think about my own insecurities he's
like all right look down oh I have a
stain on my shirt I didn't even notice
because I wasn't I was just learning
about the same person it's it's an
antidote to to like self-imposed chaos
sometimes is is you know I get being
self-conscious I get being so concerned
with what everybody else in the room is
thinking about you I mean something I
struggle with hardcore especially being
a DJ like like if I mess up in like 30
people in the room like look up at me
I'm like
like it's it's it's really how it's just
a human thing like it's like oh are
these are these 150 people in my tribe
gonna reject me do they hate me am I
gonna die on the woods by myself now
that's like our biological body is
kicking in do you think that's why
you've get that feeling then like I mean
so why be insecure are you saying yeah
like why as humans naturally because I
mean I'm sure we've all felt insecure at
some point in our life but why why do
you why is that a natural feeling for a
lot of people you know what I mean do
you think that you know good because
what I'm kind of recommending is like I
get it I see it but just don't feed it
try not to feed it yeah that's it like
and I don't want to seem like a
distraction like don't use learning
about other people as a distraction to
not feel your insecurities but a lot of
the times when we're insecure when we're
especially like public situations for me
anyway it was just because I kept
feeding it I kept like trying to find
new ways to bring it back up I kept like
trying to like reify it in in you know
also sometimes we could just try to
wrestle with it in our own heads like
you're in my head I guess I'm in like a
public place but still being insecure in
this public place when we just the same
as we're talking about you get off the
freeway and at some point you gotta be
like dude just let go the fact that that
dude cut you off because what's in front
of you just pulled home you're in your
driveway now you're happy and it's all
good in that same way like you almost
choose to stop thinking about that dude
who cut you off you almost gotta stop
choosing to think bad things about
yourself
yeah and in almost in a good antidote to
do that in a public place is to just
bright-eyed look around and just learn
about these people and just ask them and
just be genuinely interested and it's
like the more you learn about other
people and the more like you have
genuine conversations with other people
you start to learn more about yourself
you know I just I think it's a good
antidote to chaos there too yeah
absolutely it's good way to think about
it I never thought of it being like an
anecdote to chaos you know or like if
you're feeling that type of way a good
way to help you feel more comfortable
and bring yourself back to what's going
on right now
instead of being lost in your head and
all those thoughts you know is to ask
some questions you know look around
right I want to talk about without just
physical health to know I feel like
you're pretty physically healthy dude
I'm about physical health you drinking
this water what's this water about
that's a good question it's a called
King in water by this company an
adjective
it is water but it's alkalized ionized
water and pretty much I hooked this
machine up on my counter put it
connected to the tap water throughout
the faucet turn my faucet on and it goes
through this machine and it goes through
this process called electrolysis and
there's five platinum coated titanium
plates that shocked the water and when
the water shocked it so the doctor that
there's these five spots around the
world one spots in Lourdes France I
forget where the other ones are like
Tecate is Mexico or whatever it is but
there's these bodies of water that are
known to have extremely crazy health
benefits and so people lined up for
miles to get this water and live as
healthy life
a scientist sought out to find out
what's so special about this water can I
recreate it and I think like the
conclusion they came up with I could be
wrong so research it but I think that
the water was charged from like
lightning and get shocked and so it gave
this water this property this ionized
property that was really good for us and
so it shocks the water and it
restructures the water and makes it
smaller so that it's easily absorbed
into the body it makes it alkaline and
so disease can't thrive in a acidic
environment so you want your body to be
alkaline and so that's the idea behind
that and it so it gives the water o RP
which is its oxidization reduction
potential and it gives it a name
have charged so it charges this water
right and we're electric beings like
that's we're electrically that you know
we have a charge and so normal water
drinks you know that are Gatorade things
like that they're all oxidizing our body
and so when you eat an apple or you take
a bite and you leave it out sitting
there and it starts to turn brown its
oxidizing it's getting older you know so
the things that we typically consume
that are negatively charged are
oxidizing our body you know and so this
water helps preserve your body and all
of its functions it helps you if people
don't realize to like being made up
mostly of water you need water in your
life like more than you really think and
I found even just drink in any water
like if you drink and consume more water
you feel better you'll sleep better
you'll have more energy and just
everything joints yeah rushon things I
like it's it's it helps everything it's
my dad went to the doctor and had a
herniated disc and he showed me a
picture in like it looked he goes this
is where you know this is my disc this
is supposed to be water surrounding it
and this is where the disc is cracked or
whatever and I go well it looks like you
don't really have water where you should
have water what if you tried just
drinking more water and so I start
bringing him over water and his back
started feeling better you know just
from drinking water and doctors are out
here wanted to give you you know oh your
back hurts here's some pills you know
and that's a whole nother story but yeah
man waters as far as physical health
goes I think water has been the single
most important thing that I've done to
change my life for the better and I
commit to drinking a gallon of water
every day which I peel off you know it
sucks but I feel so cleansed because of
it and like it's it's one of those
things you don't know what you don't
know you know and so if you've never
drank a gallon of water and felt how
clean you feel you know you don't know
what you're missing out on right drink
your water drink your water I know I'm
always nagging on people on this podcast
to drink some water dude it's
it's just one of the easily it's the
lowest hanging fruit like come on like
yeah you know and you could install a
lot of things I always say you give
things power like every time you take a
drink of water
what if also you try to become present
what if every time you put that thing
every time it touches your lips you say
oh yeah I have lips and I have taste and
I have I have sight and I have sound and
you just take ten seconds as you drink
in your water to dislike alright
whatever thoughts that I was just like
skyrocketed towards for the last
three days I drank my last water yeah
like you could really slow yourself down
it's just a good way to get president I
president it's a good way to get present
in like I actually like I have little
catchphrases that I add like lion and
something I have like on these are my
glasses and when I think about that
that's just my word that's packed with
like oh yeah man posture posture right
like how you feeling right now like
relax the muscles that you were just
holding in your face
your shoulders are you kind of tensed up
like we're like what's your what are
your feet doing right now how your hips
kind of out of balance like how's you
how are you standing both feet on the
floor those sort of things that like you
know we don't have to or we would go mad
if we had to think about all the time
right we don't pump our heart we don't
do our organs like it's doing it for us
yeah and we are we have a lot of habits
and ways that we do things that we've
also in that same way like just you know
simplify it so we don't think about it
it's our subconscious 95% of the time
working for us so the drinking water
like whether it's at cake and how do you
spell it
Kagan hey and GE and it actually means
bring back to origin and Japanese I
think beautiful yeah it's super
beautiful and it's funny you mentioned
that to you because subconsciously when
I do drink water because I've like
personally this waters really helped out
like my yeah go ahead helped out I mean
my grandma had she had so her and my
grandpa both got diagnosed with cancer
in the same year and in that same year
they both also got diagnosed with
diabetes in the same year so it was
pretty tough my grandpa has since had
the cancer removed and has been in
remission for a while so that's good and
Mike
yeah thank you and my grandma was told
that she has this kind of cancer she's
retired nurse how's this type of cancer
that will never go away they say right
and so she's got to come in I think
every three to six months for this
checkup and kind of see if you're
growing or anything so I can't I move
back I'm starting to drink the water and
I'm posting stuff on it because I mean
my family likes their own Facebook and
so whenever I post stuff they respect my
opinion I feel like they look at that
stuff and sure enough that's what
happened my grandma says hey I want to
give this water a shot you know you're
saying that it'll be something really
cool and beneficial for me and so I was
like great and she committed to drinking
water she was drinking around a gallon a
day I don't know she was sticking to the
whole gallon and was drinking the water
for maybe like three months and went
back to the do one of her little scans
to see if her tumors have grown or
anything and they had her swallow this
dye and the dye would be absorbed into
the tumors and so you would see on a
scan where the tumors were right and if
they've grown um so the doctor was
looking at it she has the dye and stuff
and they her tumors hadn't gotten any
bigger I don't remember if they had
subsided in size or not but the doctor
looked at her and said I think that you
can say that you're in remission at this
point and so my grandma's like the only
her and her doctor both baffled but the
only thing that she's changed is
drinking the water hmm which dude I mean
if I could do if she was the only person
that benefited from the water like it
just feels so good you know and I
remember my grandpa my dad telling me
the story but was going through all this
and my grandpa told my dad I don't know
what I would do without her you know and
like at that time too I didn't assume
the responsibility but I felt who am i
if I've got this water and I know that
it does it said to do this for you and I
don't share it with her you know what I
mean and so believing in herself just
like we were saying earlier
you got it like if you have that little
intuition of like dude like what what's
it gonna hurt like are people gonna like
try to like make fun of me and say that
I'm wrong like cool whatever like you
can say that I'm wrong or you can think
whatever you want if you've never
learned things that I've learned you
haven't done the research that's fine
yeah like it's like why wouldn't I help
this person yeah it was amazing and her
her diabetes also she doesn't have to
take insulin as much so I'm not really
familiar with diabetes how it works but
I know a little bit and I know that when
she started drinking the water her
insulin levels or whatever levels it is
that they checked blood sugar something
like that
stabilized and so she didn't have to
take as much insulin and it was more on
a scheduled basis that she would be
taking it and then I remember her one
day she was saying you know I had she
goes last night I had some M&Ms before
bed and I was sure my blood sugar would
be super high when I woke up and she
checked it and it was like 53 or
something like that which I guess is
really good and so she's like all I've
been doing is drinking the water and so
she's like you know you crave it at that
point you know right I mean we're
biological creatures like we we really
do accidentally like just because we're
so we're so separated from our like food
supply it's like you go to the store to
get your food but like the long process
of how it even got there and how it's
made and how was thought of and how it's
like all this stuff food water
everything we consume we kind of do
forget that it's like what constructs
who we are like it's wellness you know
like we don't really fully understand
the human consciousness but as someone
who has suffered severely from
depression like like the the food that
you eat the the things that you drink
like that all affects your thoughts yeah
it's it's like like if I've been
drinking for four days in a row like the
fifth day it's like it's very hard to
find that like super positive optimistic
side of me ya know in you know I think
it all just comes full circle like our
bodies are magic man like think about
what they're doing they're doing they're
just right now my heart's beating my
lungs are just just going in and out
they know exactly the amount of air that
I need
oxygen and co2 - like what the you
know we we think about health and we
think about food and what we consume
like the quality of our water and
everything we think of it a lot of times
we don't really address it unless it's
either it tastes good or bad or it's
going to give me weight on my physical
body or not in now I always just try to
emphasize like don't think about food in
your body I'm like a weight scale like
physical yeah like how do you feel like
and you know when you eat healthy you
start to notice and when you when you
like drink healthy and you'd like to
limit how much I'll call your in taking
and all and you start taking care of
your body you start noticing that like
you're you just start feeling better and
what does that mean like that's you know
that's we say that as such a blanket
term but it's one of the most important
things when you feel better
you have less anger towards your kids
and your dog in you it doesn't hurt as
much when you get out of bed and your
knee doesn't creak as much and you're
able to stay up for an hour longer
because you're not as exhausted and
there's so many different things that
like your life can compound if you
wanted to start a business if you wanted
to like I want to be an entrepreneur but
I work eight hours a day if you only got
two hours a day to work on your business
well they're gonna be served a lot
better if you're sharp if you're focused
if you're hydrated if you're drinking
your water man it's this it's it's great
that's really cool thanks for sharing
that story pac-man's yeah it's funny too
because like as far as like healthy
eating and things like that like I'm
very lucky I've got a really fast
metabolism and growing up you know I
didn't have home-cooked meals things
like that I I got whatever it is that I
could and we were talking earlier - I
felt like a burden as far as like being
another mouth to feed if I was at a
friend's house or something so you know
are you hungry can I make you something
no I'm fine thanks you know and I don't
want to be a burden and so with that
growing up for like a good chunk of my
life my dad can cook some mean
enchiladas but that's about it and we
ate out a lot you know what I mean I was
always eating fast food and things like
that
and luckily my metabolism is so quick
you know I didn't it's not that I gained
a bunch of weight or anything like that
but beyond that I realized that
processed foods they're not good for you
and it's like the compound effect you
know if you're continuously doing that
I'm young right now my body's like
efficient you know everything's working
good so it can break down those foods
and like use it as it needs to and it'll
be fine
but when I'm 50 if I'm still doing that
my body's not going to be in the same
shape it's in and you know maybe maybe
I've got blood clots or I have a heart
attack or something at a really young
age from eating all this stuff and so
I've recently had myself a nice bowl of
spinach raw spinach before I came here
and a couple bananas and so I do
intermittent fasting every day so we had
not every day that's a lie but we can
talk touch on that but I typically don't
eat till about one o'clock and so when
you're fasting I haven't done a bunch of
research on like extended fast or
anything like that but I do know that
you want to break your fast with like a
fruit or something really like a juice
maybe something light on your stomach
you don't want to go straight to KFC and
just eat a bunch of greasy chicken
certainly so I've been making it a point
to break a fast with some fruit and
eating a lot more fruit and veggies I
started with like blending a bunch of
spinach in like a shake or whatever but
like I now know now that I know it's
feeling my body and it's good for me I
like love the taste of spinach taste
like it's just green that's the best way
to explain what tastes like you know
it's not very for most people it's not
that good but like I crave it it's
really it is good right I think that the
more that you convince your like
convince your body and like learn about
things and you're like like the more
your like is about as you're about to
eat that that bite of a spinach you tell
your brain it's like dude this is good
this makes me feel good this makes my
tummy happy which makes my brain happy
and it's balances my serotonin and I
love that like the more you do that the
more it's like you you see these things
that's less like it I don't want that
cuz I want cheese burger mouth pleasure
I don't want green spinach mouth
pleasure I want cheese burger mouth
pleasure like you got a you you can like
train your brain to know that it's
healthy for you and as you're like
thinking of those like for higher
consciousness parts of yourself rather
than like the lower like give me this
food so I can feel the most comfortable
and all these dopamine releases right
now like I just want yeah I'm gonna hey
I love it too but it's it's a it's a
training you know it's where we're in a
crazy like the fact that we can I can
get in my car or even go for a walk and
go get like Burger King McDonald's they
get all these like foods that like they
says you know they taste just delicious
and you crave them like but the feeling
that you feel afterwards like that does
say something cuz you know after I have
like a steak and some veggies and like
it's delicious too like I don't feel all
shitty afterwards that's like what's
that about you know so I feel like the
burger that you have or whatever and
like because for a lot of the time when
I was lifted and I was trying to gain
weight and everything is like eat
anything and everything that you
possibly can and so dirty book I'm just
you know going to jack-in-the-box Burger
King and I'm eating all this food in
these empty calories and like I'm
feeling so bloated so I go to bed like
yeah I did my job like I should be
gaining weight but like as I switched to
eating more I still eat you know greasy
food don't get me wrong but it's a it's
all about balance but when I get full on
fruit and veggies and stuff my stomach
doesn't feel bloated you know it's more
of a my stomach's full but it's more of
like a flat full you know what I mean
that like you said that tells you
something yeah I mean nature has made
these things in such a peculiar way that
they seem to work for our body like it
you know it's a an apple has the right
amount of you know fiber and it for us
to break it down but when we take an
apple and we make it into apple juice
our body doesn't process it the same way
that it would if we ate an apple because
it doesn't have the fiber it just has
like the sugars from it and it tastes I
didn't know that yeah yeah I mean I mean
double look that yeah I feel like
Buttrick I mean guys I make sensible
anyway like our body we have such a
complicated process in there and I think
that a lot of the times were consuming
things day by day by day
I'm not giving our body like a break to
like work properly and you know there's
there's so many documentaries that you
can watch like that sugar doc you're
that sugar film I think it's on Amazon
Prime if you haven't seen that one
that's a good one they explain a lot I
think like how like insulin works or how
like what our body does with these
leftover like sugar fats in the in the
glucose and like what what it ends up
doing like once our body gets full of
like okay I can't process any more of
that or I don't need any more in here
and then like it kind of shows you they
lay out kind of what your body does to
it afterwards and it's like oh that's
why I feel I would love to see that
because that that sugar film yeah yeah
that's it's weird too and I mean it
might get a little weird but yeah weird
like your your gut tells you a lot about
how healthy you are you know in like a
really good way it's funny my girlfriend
her dad he's passed now but like one
thing he's always say is like you should
be able to enjoy your poop you know you
should have should be able to sit down
and like have a good poof and I think
that it's weird but like it tells you a
lot about how you how your body is doing
you know and like if you're eating a
bunch of processed foods and stuff it's
not enjoyable you're lacking the fiber
and stuff that you're talking about that
does whatever it's supposed to do you
know to make that thing okay and to be
candid with you that was like the first
sign when I was like I need to take more
of a serious approach with what I'm
eating is like when I didn't start
enjoying my poops you know what I mean
and it's like you're suffering in the
bathroom yeah you will your exams gotta
give the disease like it begins in the
gut and there's a so the guy that
co-created the colonoscopy won't see any
of his patients without them first
drinking cake in water for 30 days or
something like that
and so the reason why is because it
detox is your body at such a level and
like your colon specifically it will
cleanse it out in such a way where a lot
of the problems a lot of people have
would be solved if they were drinking
the right water or
enough water and so knowing that I was
like you know I can't just act like it's
not happening you know because I look
fine or whatever on the outside you know
something's going on inside my body and
if I don't address it now it's maybe
it'll be too late you know what I mean
or it'll be a life-or-death situation at
that point and so well I think that
people don't dude for me we identify
with everything we do and we also
separate ourselves from the things that
we don't want to like like I would eat
crappy for a long time and then I would
be I'd be farty I'd be gassy I'd have
like multiple poops during the day and
they weren't pleasant they were just
like just riveting in and I oh you know
of course that food makes me feel like a
little bit different but like I just
have a shitty digestion my digestive
system you know I just like I would I
would just explain my way out of it if
like well that's just how my body in mah
mah blah and then like you start really
eating healthy or you start like I
started fasting you know help my body a
ton start to like heal again because
when I was younger I did it so much
buckin fast food I worked at the mall
when I was 16 and like it was like every
meal like I mean three meals a day you
eat like some fast food or like food
court stuff but so I think I think like
starting to really get in tune with how
you feel is something that like seems so
obvious but a lot of us don't really
stop or slow down to think about it but
Oh true yeah if you're hey if you're in
the bathroom listener like all the right
now if you're in the bathroom if you're
pooping right now is terrible like you
know let's talk food no I but if you you
know if you go to the restroom and
you're your stomach's bloated you're you
have inflammation all the time it's been
here you're gassy you you burp a lot you
know it's like like you know when I
drink when I'm drinking beer like I
start getting Burpee and that's just you
know your body is just processing it
differently than it would water right
and it's not it's not like as soon as
you start burping it's like oh no I'm
killing myself this is terrible it's
like notice if you're Burpee 24/7 are
you consuming something you shouldn't be
24/7 yeah just your diet affects so many
other things in too
me when I'm not inflamed man like my my
brain feels so much more clear when I'm
not just covered in inflammation so true
and you mentioned earlier to like your
thoughts are better when you're eating
better like it's so true it's so
correlated that's crazy yes which is
easy that's just I mean that's just
crazy like that's I wish that I could
like scientifically weave the gap with
one sentence right there like how does
getting better food make you not want to
die as much there's something I want to
fasting I so fasting I stumbled into
intermittent fasting so typically mine
is stop eating at some point like let's
say stop eating at 9:00 and then the
next day I don't like set a timer I
don't like thoroughly follow it I'm
pretty blessed like you know work from
home for the most part but I like I
don't eat til like probably like two or
so sometimes one but essentially I try
to get over I think it's 14 hours in my
head like I check I'm like oh I'm
feeling kind of hunger has it been 14
hours yes or no I don't know the exact
like windows when it comes to like 12 14
16 but I do know that I feel better I'm
less distracted like once I'm in that
fasting zone like those last few hours
before you eat like I feel like I'm
cognitively just a jeans I don't
even want to eat roast like I don't know
I'm so focused and so energetic it's
nuts so convince my listeners who have
never tried fasting one more thing
actually before we get into that I want
you to convince listeners to fast
but I will say for me one thing when it
comes to like looking back at like my
childhood or looking back at like okay
what have I learned that's not helping
me what am i doing then I can unlearn
and do something differently so when it
came to eating I actually had my mom is
like a huge her mother was diabetic and
she passed away from that my mom's like
a huge hypochondriac when it comes to
things like this I remember just
repeating my sisters would say my mom
would say it if you feel if you're like
feeling dizzy and you haven't eaten in a
while
your blood Sugar's probably low you need
to get some food in you and so like I
had this thing where it's like if it had
been like four hours since I've eaten I
would start to get panic cuz my god my
blood Sugar's low
and it's not like I was like say it out
loud so much but it's almost
this background thought that I didn't
realize that I had always had of like I
would almost get like panicky if it
hasn't been a few hours since I'd eaten
so when I first started to fast I was
like am I like sick like yeah I feel
kind of like I'm hungry I'm kind of
shaky like in my own like am I gonna die
like my diabetic and I haven't confirmed
it like blah blah blah but eventually
you start telling your body it's kinda
like being in a sauna right you're like
yeah I'm hot man it's I'm not gonna die
though it's okay I'm safe you start
telling your body like okay it's not the
blood sugar thing it's not you're not
you're not dying you're used to eating
very often but you know you've done the
research you've watched these videos
there's tons of people who do it I've
got some emergency walnuts right here if
I'm really feeling I'm gonna pass out or
something but exploring the fasting
thing I'm like pushing your edges and
like man is oh it's been nine hours
since I've eaten I actually you know
I've been kind of working and like
keeping busy I really don't feel that
starving so for me I just wanted to
unwind the fact that I had a belief that
I didn't realize that I really had that
was like running why I would never try
fasting because I thought my blood sugar
could be low so so me on fasting is well
though as you mentioned the hardest is
the first week or two you know as your
body gets used to this new schedule that
you have with eating in this new
relationship I guess with eating that
you have and it's for most people
completely different than what they're
used to they're used to waking up eating
breakfast breakfast is the most
important meal of the day I know it's
not just a thing that people say like
why do people say that yeah and then I
mean it makes sense now to people people
say breakfast break fast it's when
you're breaking your fast you know and
so intermittent fasting it's really
simple it's not as crazy and as people
make it out to be but if you want to
lose weight if you want to gain muscle
sleep better think better have radiation
reduce inflammation I mean there's
endless reasons why someone should
benefit but I mean give in a minute
fasting a try for a month you know and I
have no doubts that you'll feel better
and it's it's simple the like you were
saying all you got to do is stop eating
around eight to ten you know and the
hours can fluctuate you mainly want
fast for at least 14 to 16 hours and you
don't eat the next day you push
breakfast back until like 1 or 2
depending and some days I go longer some
days you know if I'm gonna be a little
bit busy or not have a chance to eat
I'll eat earlier so it's not like a
cookie cutter thing or anything like
that but that's how it formed to me it
wasn't like this like okay I'm following
this strictly yeah it didn't seem like I
was on like a 30-day diet plan and like
okay did I write my never have my reps
down like it wasn't like that I feel
like for me it was just like okay I'm
just gonna make the decision like unless
that unless that watch says 2:00 p.m.
I'm not gonna eat so like any time that
my brain convinced me that I need food
I'm gonna say you okay but you're fine
yeah you're gonna be fine and then
you're like you don't need to change
what you're eating either that's the
beautiful part of it you know you can
keep eating whatever you're eating and
you'll see you'll still be able to see
benefits if you give it a chunk of time
right which is super cool I mean of
course breaking your fast with like
Burger King every day might not be the
best right everybody but he'll it's
probably better than waking up after
having eaten six hours ago
yeah and just even more Burger King I
forget what point you reach this but I
and I might be butchering I think it's
called the tofu G or something like that
and I think it might be like 15-20 hours
18 hours somewhere and you're fast where
your body actually starts to take your
bad cells and turn them like recycle
them and they'll be either you know
thrown into the trash or they'll the
toxins will be removed from that cell
and it'll regenerate as a healthy cell
right and so it's it's amazing you said
earlier about how crazy and magical our
bodies are but really we have no idea
how magical our bodies really are and
like I think too that when I first heard
about intermittent fasting the I think
the guys name was Greg Gallagher kino
body I don't know if you've seen his ads
on YouTube or anything the last name
sounds familiar yeah well not to be
mistaken with Frank out yeah I know
that's I think that's why it stands out
though yeah but he he was talking about
you know our and
Esther's there the way that they did
things were they woke up and they didn't
eat and they would go all day not eating
and they would be hunting and they'd
need to be sharp to hunt and see and
then once they made their kill or
whatever that's when they would feast at
nighttime so I mean it's interesting to
look at it that way but we're not it's
not a new concept for humans to not eat
all that all day long you know what I
mean right yeah it's always blessed to
just eat whatever whenever yeah it
really is like it's another one of those
things that it's like wait hold up who
is it that says that I need to eat three
square meals a day who is it that says
that breakfast at this particular time I
mean break fast breakfast I love when
people separate that because I'm like oh
yeah it is because you know when you so
maybe breakfast is the most important
meal a day but that doesn't mean has to
be in the morning yeah it could be like
when you when you break your fast yeah
that's an important one but like that
could be at 2:00 p.m.
mm-hmm yeah like that whatever we're
getting kind of up here in time do you
have to pee and within the next 20 or so
yeah but I do want to let's make sure we
cover anything that you want to make
sure you spread to the people but also I
figured just casually like what do you
think about the world right now like
what the is happening
are we on fire is it the pan is it the
apocalypse and we what's what's your hot
take on the world death I think it's no
secret I don't want to get too into
politics or anything like that but it's
no secret it's a crazy time to be alive
right now without touching too much on
like what's going on specifically in the
world and how like what I believe about
it first of all I believe I will say
this and have no problem saying this but
like I pride myself on the fact that
I've got a strong immune system because
I've been exposed to so much stuff as a
child like my dad was a single dad like
I said very busy I didn't have like all
my I mean I had shots that you had to
have the police force and go to school
and stuff the like I didn't have like
excessive shots I wasn't taking all
these trips to the doctor and
doing all these things is very natural
the way that like life was for me and I
mean I was a boy so like I was into a
bunch of stuff as a kid I'm always like
my hands or my mouth or whatever you
know and like I think being exposed to
all that stuff and being sick playing
baseball in the rain things like that it
made my immune system stronger and so
like I personally and I get like other
people are in different situations and
like I'm you gotta be courteous with
people that I'll have their immune
systems kind of compromised you know and
stuff like that but you I love to get
exposed to things because I feel that it
gives my body a chance to like get
stronger now with that being said the
light shall set you free the book that I
was talking about another thing that
like it kind of instilled in me is like
you're here at this particular time for
a reason and like I don't know what that
reason is right now but I mean I know
some of my strengths and I like to try
to play out to my strengths and I think
I do believe that like I am and we are
all here for a specific reason and this
chaotic crazy time in this world and
like I like to believe that what's going
on right now is like purging the
negativity and the bad stuff away from
us and that needs to be done in order
for like a beautiful new life to come
about for us you know and so I think
that it's its craziest chaotic and do
what you need to do to like find peace
in this time but like have half faith
and like believe that it's not always
gonna be like this and there is a chance
for like a brighter tomorrow you know
what I mean right right yeah I agree
mana that's a great outlook I think I
think for me like it's hard to like know
where I stand of like you know and not
unlike the specific issues like at this
particular moment there's like like the
riots there's protesting you know
there's a lot of stuff going on with
racism Mike but the you know the fact
that we have a pandemic and the fact
that
we handled it so poorly and the fact
that we have a pandemic and our leaders
aren't telling us how to better take
care of our bodies and they're not
teaching us about vitamin D and they're
not teaching us about our immune systems
and what to do to strengthen our immune
systems and Here I am like you know you
listen to politicians talk about just
like stupid stuff that does isn't
relevant at the point or they're trying
to defend themselves from what the Dems
are the Lim said or whatever but why
aren't we just telling each other like
alright guys so yet there's a virus
where it's not entirely sure how it got
here but I know that we have a better
chance of survival on an individual
level if we're all stronger so here's
some daily workouts here's some
stretches here's some ways to improve
your immune system oh this points of
finger at the craziness that is our food
system because our food is making us
more susceptible to get this virus and
not more unhealthy well let's take a
look at that like those are the things
that should be sparking up to me I
totally agree I so so so what I mean my
point there is it's really easy
to feel helpless
I have you know a lot of people just
like based on personality types like
INFJs but I am so like I have a thing
that I can't explain but I care about
humanity and it's and I'm not trying to
sound cool I'm not trying to sound like
it's on this specific individual level
it's like since I was born I just like
have a caring about the bigger picture
I just like want this what we're doing
on earth to happen and still happen and
in continuing and thrive and grow and
it's just thing inside of a lot of
people I'm sure you have the same damn
thing yeah it's it's but so I think that
you know with all this madness and you
know we get so caught up and what the
media is telling us to do and not do and
what social media is is pushing us
towards and what other people's opinions
are I think that on an individual basis
like we got to just like look at what we
can control like what what's in our
everyday life like what can we do what
weird conversations can we have what
like is our grandmother one that's being
kind of racist like maybe let's have
that conversation that's on us like
let's and when it comes outside of that
stuff like when it comes to the whole
the whole bigger picture of like why are
we all here like trying to argue against
each other and prove who's more left or
who's more rider who's correct in this
way because of this
like I don't think that that's helpful
I think what's helpful is finding ways
to communicate on our individual level
and like how are you taking care of your
body and when you learn things about
your body and they help how can you be
like telling your friends about that how
can you be helping the community around
you and taking thinking of things
logically I think we get so projected
with you know especially at this time
like with technology man we there's so
much power by people who aren't the best
people to like project us into areas
aren't really like our own to to get us
to be obsessing over the wrong things so
I guess just for me with this whole
situation going on I just feel helpless
but I also think that it's important to
remind everybody just like use your five
senses and look what's what's right in
front of you and don't let these
get you all mad don't let
these get you to fight
their fights for them you know we've
we've got to do unusual things at
unusual times and you know you don't
always asking nice questions isn't
always how you get the answers like
sometimes you got to go outside and
you know grab someone by the
collar and tell them like wake up and we
have our version of that as humanity
going on right now which i think is
important but I I I'm a form for me I'm
kind of like okay we're descending into
madness like the way somehow our ability
to make sense of things is like not in a
lot of us are seeing it like we're we're
smart people a lot of people listen this
podcasts are like you know between the
age of 20 and 30 and I think that a lot
of our like you millennial age and stuff
is able to look around and be like dude
people are not communicating like we see
that like they're arguing about these
things and you're like you guys aren't
even talking about the same thing you're
just like arguing with other people's
points that they were fed to you so I
don't know I can perceiving them and the
way that we're where we're at you know
you mentioned that before the podcast
too and I thought that was a really good
point you know where somebody you could
probably say it better than I can but
somebody can tell you
the same thing but the way that you know
their intention behind it might be
different than the way that you perceive
what it is that they're saying right and
I think there's a lot of that going on
right now to where you know people are
screaming at each other one thing and
they're taking it a different way than
what that person is trying to intend for
the brain
oh I'll use the same analogy that I used
which is I'll say as a white person
talking to a white friend I feel
uncomfortable talking about this because
I feel like it's not my place and I feel
like it's not my argument and I don't
want to I don't want to incorrectly
represent something that I don't know
enough about to be a face of so I'll say
that but um just as an example in
analogy like let's say kneeling for the
national anthem so what like when Colin
Kapernick was kneeling during during the
national anthem what he is doing why he
is kneeling the reason why is because of
the because of the racism because of the
injustice because of well you know
putting it in in this situation because
of you know police violence against like
he doesn't feel as safe so that's why
he's kneeling well on the other side of
the world the people who don't know him
they don't know his culture they don't
know or give a about his life about
his the life of his family members about
the life of the people that he grew up
with the you know oppression that they
had to deal with they don't they don't
know or care which is you know we've all
got a lot of stuff going on their own
individual lives like we can't be
expected to know every single person's
version of everything in the entire
world but so when he kneeled when he
starts kneeling he's and he knows what
he's fighting for and he tells us here's
why I'm kneeling right and that's so he
tells us here's why here's my meaning of
why I'm doing this right well the people
on the other side who oppose it who are
arguing with this are saying the flag
means this to me when you kneel during
the national anthem means this to me and
on their version let's say for this is a
broad brushstroke but say cuz a more
conservative person I'm not trying to
talk about politics conservatives but
when you see someone kneeling when
there's a flag
what you think is you're spitting on my
grandfather's face who's a veteran you
are you you are disgracing the dead
soldiers who died to get you to even be
able to play football so that's where
they're coming from which is not a miss
truth it's it's you know maybe it's it's
energetically charged in a certain way
because maybe they have like you know
your uncle your grandma was like served
in the force has lost their life so you
can have this but so in in in what I'm
saying is the real issue so the
conservative people the people on this
side are saying you're spitting on the
face of veterans and this person is
saying I'm not even talking about that
I'm not even that has nothing to do with
me I'm saying I'm not going to do this
because there's so much oppression and
racism still so he so he the person
kneeling Colin in this situation Colin
Kaepernick is saying I'm fighting this
oppression and the people are taking the
exact same situation happening in real
time and saying no it doesn't mean that
it means this but what they're both
meaning neither one of them are actually
saying directly we need to fight racism
right and so we're arguing about what
things mean in like coming out each
other from ways that we can't even solve
problems because we're talking over each
other's heads because we think that we
know what each other means and to me I
just think that we're intelligent enough
we're smart enough we know enough we've
our consciousness as like a
planet has grown enough to where we need
to start having people who are like guys
stop being childish stop stop in again
I'm not saying the riots and stuff for
childish that's not I'm saying I'm
saying our communication is being like
broken down and we're smarter than this
like we need to be able to have real
conversations and I think in order for
that to happen more people on an
individual level need to be able to
recognize when they're getting angry
when they're getting unnhhh on control
of their emotions when they've been
eating Burger King for 16 days so their
brain on the 17th day just isn't as
clear as someone who's eating kale salad
every day like I don't know there's just
a lot of there's a lot of
miscommunication that really could be
simplified and that's what I'm seeing
I'm seeing
a lot of people yell at each other in
there having the same conversation
they're green on the same thing but
they're still fighting and you know I
was listening to you Brett Weinstein
who's an evolutionary biologist I
recommend his podcast a dark-horse
podcast but he was essentially like the
way that he put it and I want to explain
this in more detail but I don't it's
like a it's a thing that started to
click to me like a couple days ago is
like we think that World War three is
going to be like not that we like know
what's gonna happen right but we think
World War three would be like with guns
and we're gonna fight and stuff but like
World War three might be going on right
now and may not be versus other
countries it might be because of our
algorithms because of the things
that we're reading the things that are
on social media the things that are on
news the things that we're consuming the
instances that are like movies are
making us feel and stuff like we're kind
of fighting like a an inner battle
against like true algorithms an AI in
like you I'm not sure if a lot of people
understand how influential and like
poised all of the information that you
read is like if you like in this
household we believe this but my
neighbors literally might have a hundred
percent literally everything they see on
their Twitter newsfeed might be that
different than mine because that's how
the date that's how the algorithms work
and they feed us so I think we're
basically getting we're in World War
three is what I'm saying and we're
getting fed like the the data
and the algorithms and our social media
news consumption technology is feeding
like weird sides of our biases and it's
making us take off our glasses and
fistfight even though we should have our
glasses on and have conversation look
each other's eyes and say what is it
that you want here yeah like what what
is it you know we're we're having this
big miscommunication and again I'll just
round out like I feel uncomfortable like
talking about the protests and stuff
because I don't know where what my
opinion on is it on it is I don't know
I'm struggling to I'm struggling to like
feel like what I have to say is
important but I'm also like it
immediately like I don't really know
what I think about it like I'm trying to
work it out like I'm I'm a promise like
I'm watching the videos and watch
YouTube and I have notes up there that
I'm trying to like work through my own
like thoughts on the subjects and stuff
like I'm not saying that I have it right
I'm not saying that my opinion is
important I'm not saying that and you
know whatever I guess I'm just kind of
like cover my butt here I'm afraid of
like someone just taking my words and
misconstruing them but I think you I
think you put it in a really good way
yeah I just there's a part have you seen
Hunger Games these there's a part at the
end where or part like when the last
movies were like the leader
she's like turn you're like they're
fighting each other or whatever and they
think they have to fight each other in
The Hunger Games right it's us it's the
12 districts or whatever against each
other but in the end she like once a
cart start getting more sensible it's
like wait we don't have to fight each
other this isn't even like a fight we
should be in turn your weapons at the
Capitol like I remember it like it
always stood out to me which like turn
your weapons at the Capitol and it makes
me think like you know not not
government like not down with all
government's because I'm not trying to
be an anarchist here but I'm saying like
we're fighting each other and we
shouldn't be fighting each other there's
something else like going on that could
be solved here yeah so true you put that
in a good way
yeah I try thanks for letting me rap and
ramble too you buddy yeah I appreciate
you sharing your thoughts and I think
that there was a lot of value people
could get from them I hope so
I just want to offer my perspective and
I don't think you know I don't think any
of us should be afraid to offer our
perspective if we really are trying to
be level-headed like I'm not trying to
hurt anybody's feelings I'm not trying
to I'm just trying to figure it out too
like I don't know what's going on but
this this whole thing is weird
man this is we all feel this weirdness
we're all super uncomfortable for the we
don't know what our future looks like we
don't know what truth is because media
is crazy I think we just need to take a
step back and just like okay what what
are we doing here like right in front of
us like what's going on what
misconceived and misconstrued ideas I
mean accidentally having about the
person next to me like this is my
brothers and sisters here we're all
humans were in this together like we got
it we got to figure this out and and be
the smartest version of ourselves you
know that's what I think amen to that we
do the human race you know we're all the
same race yeah
regardless of color or anything like
that you know
human yeah yeah yeah before the the
culture spiked and before the before the
differences that we do have were human
right so we need to we need to remember
that and fall back on that and see how
we can figure this out together because
you know I want the I want the future of
the planet to be yeah that's the only
way we can do it if we come together and
figure out a solution you know that
works for all of us right yeah cool all
right Dave well I appreciate you man
thanks for coming on
appreciate you having me bro I love
everything you got going on here all
right thank you bro appreciate that
listeners drink some water bring some
water drink more water don't eat till 2
o'clock tomorrow and stop eating tonight
at 9:00 or 10:00 hell yeah all right bro
I appreciate you I appreciate you
brother my friends I hope you enjoyed
the episode if you did consider sharing
it just take a screen recording
take a clip send the whole link copy it
send it to a friend send it to your
social media send it to your mom send it
to your dad set it to your grandma I
don't care just share it if you did
enjoy it and consider giving it a five
star review rating on the Apple Apple
podcast Apple music whatever Spotify
follow it on Spotify thumbs up on
YouTube all those typical things just
share it interact with it if you did
enjoy it I hope you're doing well take
care of yourself drink some water
stretch give yourself some self-love you
deserve it peace out we'll see you next
week
you